外挂字幕由 美剧迷 / www.mjmtv.top 合并官方中英双语
替我向莎拉问好
Give Sarah my love.
多处撕裂伤
...multiple lacerations.
看看我女儿,她才五岁
My daughter, she's five years old.
嘿
Hey. It's okay.
没事了,这里是医院
You're in the hospital.
Are you in pain?
你身上痛吗?
我们可以给你注射止痛药
We can give you something.
艾莉!
Ellie! Ellie!
好了,艾莉,好了
- 好了 - 艾莉
Here.
没事了
It's okay.
最后生还者第二季 第3集
(三个月后)
一到十级,你的疼痛有几级?
And how would you rate your pain? Scale of one to ten?
不疼,零级
- Nothing. Zero. - Zero.
零级,已经很好了
Can't ask for much more than that.
来吧,最后一次肺功能检查
Okay. One last PFT.
你看
Look at that.
Yeah.
不错
Alright.
挺好的,就是今天了
Today's the day.
- 那我可以... - 就快了
- So, can I just-- - Almost.
I just need you to see one more person, then you're good to go.
你还得见一个人,然后就能出院了
我的老天爷
Oh, for fuck's sake.
- 你好吗? - 挺好的
- How are you doing? - Fine.
回答这么快就是不好的表现
If you say it that fast, it kind of implies you're not.
Okay, ask me again.
好吧,再问我一遍
艾莉,你好吗?
How are you doing, Ellie?
让我想想,这事很复杂 毕竟感觉这东西...
Give me a moment.
It's really complicated 'cause, you know, feelings.
Okay.
好吧
拜托,我一直被困在这里,自从...
Oh, come on, man, I've been stuck in here since...
没错,我想他 他对我来说很重要,我既伤心又难过
Yeah, I miss him. He meant a lot to me.
So, yeah. Upset and sad.
当然
Of course.
但我好奇的是跨年夜的事
But I was actually wondering about New Year's Eve.
你们两个在舞会上吵架了 那是你最后一次和他说话吗?
You two got into it at the dance.
Was that the last time you spoke to him?
是
Yeah.
我回家时,他站在门廊上
When I got home, he was on the porch,
and I should've talked to him, but I didn't.
我该跟他聊聊的,但我没有
- 你后悔吗? - 当然后悔
- Do you regret that? - Yeah, of course.
But your final moment with someone doesn't define your whole time with them.
但你和一个人最后相处的时光
不能定义你们整体的关系
道理是这个道理,但事实往往如此
It shouldn't, but it often does.
在我和乔尔相处的最后时光里 他曾说...
In my last moment with Joel, he said he
他对不起你
wronged you.
可能很严重
Maybe bad.
他说他干什么了吗?
What is it that he said that he did?
问题就在这儿,他的话前后不搭
Well, that's the thing. It didn't really make sense.
他说“我救了她”
He said, "I saved her."
他救过我很多次
He saved me a lot of times.
对,换我也会这么想 但那不算“对不起”
Yeah, I would think so. But that's not wronging someone.
真奇怪
That's weird.
我不知道他什么意思
No idea what he meant.
我没觉得他对不起我
I don't feel wronged.
不管他说的是什么 真希望我能放过他
Man, I wish I could have let him off the hook
for whatever it was he was talking about.
现在我只能放过自己了
I guess I'll have to let myself off the hook for that.
你做得很好了
Well, you really are doing good.
见鬼
Shit, if everyone were as healthy as you, what would I do for weed and booze?
如果人人都像你这么健康 我还怎么换取大麻和酒啊?
不用担心,这镇上还有很多操蛋的人
I wouldn't worry, Gail, there's still a lot of fucked up people
- in this town. - Yeah.
对,但你不是
But not you, though.
(米勒)
(乔尔,谢谢你做的一切)
艾莉?
Ellie?
Fuck.
妈的
我来了
Yeah, I'm coming.
我去医院了
I went to the hospital.
他们什么时候让你出院的?
When'd they let you out?
- Thirty minutes ago. - Nice.
- 30分钟前 - 很好
他们让我见盖尔了
They made me talk to Gail.
我从来没说...
I never said--
你来看了我那么多次 我早该说谢谢了
I should have said thank you
for all those times you came to visit.
That's okay. You would have done the same for me.
不用客气 换我住院,你也会来看我的
- Yeah, maybe not as often. - Yeah, no, probably not.
- 对,也许不会那么频繁 - 是啊,可能不会
I made you cookies.
我做了饼干给你吃
为什么?
- Just 'cause? - No.
算是一份和解礼吧
This is a peace offering.
因为我要让你生气了
Because I'm about to make you angry.
在医院里...
In the hospital,
你曾问过我
when you asked me about that day,
那天的事...
我说我没听到任何有用的信息
I told you I didn't learn anything useful.
其实我没说实话
That wasn't true.
我知道他们大部分人的名字 也知道他们是哪里来的
I know most of their names, and I know where they're from.
你听我说完
Please, just listen. The doctors told me not to upset you.
- 医生叫我不要让你太激动 - 我不在乎
- I don't give a fuck. - And I knew that if I told you
我知道我一旦说出他们在哪 你会拔掉输液管
where they were, you'd just start pulling your tubes out
爬也要爬过去找他们
and crawling on your hands and knees to get there.
I don't give a fuck.
我不在乎
你浪费了我们的时间 你让他们逃走了
You cost us time. You let them get away.
首先
First of all,
几个星期以来 这镇上一片狼藉,到处都是葬礼
this town was wreckage and funerals for weeks.
Nobody was gonna go after anyone.
没人会去追杀任何人
然后我突然想到
And then it occurred to me, if you wanna find someone,
如果你想找一个人 而你只知道对方最终的目的地...
and the only thing you know about them is where they're gonna end up.
还不如让对方先到了再说
Maybe let them get there.
我也爱他
I loved him too, you know.
好吧,我们先说名字
Okay, let's start with names.
那个黑发男叫曼尼 另一个男的叫欧文
The dark-haired guy was Manny. The other guy was Owen.
The girl with the dark hair and the bald one,
黑发女孩和光头女孩里有一个叫诺拉
one of them's named Nora. I'm not sure which.
- 我不确定是哪个 - 那个扎辫子的女孩?
The girl with the braid?
艾比
Abby.
他们来自什么地方?
Where are they from?
我在一个背包上看到了一块布章
I saw a patch on a backpack.
黄色三角,有个狼头...
Yellow triangle, wolf's head,
还有三个字母,WLF
and the letters W-L-F.
And then, I remembered a story Eugene told me from back when he was a Firefly.
我记得尤金给我讲过 他还在火萤时的一个故事
He said that there were these small regional groups
他说有些地区性小团体 都想对抗联邦救灾局
in the West all trying to fight FEDRA,
and how stupid it was that they didn't just join together.
还说他们没有联合起来真够蠢的
其中一个团体就是华盛顿解放阵线
One of those groups was the Washington Liberation Front.
来自西雅图
Out of Seattle.
WLF,狼
W-L-F. Wolf.
Fucking morons.
一群傻逼
- 他有说这个团体有多小吗? - 没说
- Did he say how small they were? - No.
But seeing as how no one's ever mentioned them since,
不过,既然从那以后没人提过他们
I'm guessing small enough for us to handle.
我猜应该是我们能应付的小团体
还有谁知道这事?
Who else knows?
Just us.
就我们俩
我没打算在告诉你之前告诉任何人
I wasn't gonna tell anyone before you.
现在怎么办?
So, now what?
怎么样?
Well?
我得考虑一下
I gotta think about this.
考虑什么?我们去干掉那些家伙
Think about what? Let's fucking get these guys.
Ellie, it ain't that simple.
艾莉,事情没那么简单
The town is still recovering.
小镇还在恢复中,你也一样
- So are you. - We get where you're coming from--
- 我们明白你的出发点 - 不,我们不明白
No, we don't get where you're coming from. I don't get where you're coming from.
我不明白,如果死的人是你 乔尔早在天亮前就赶往西雅图了
If it had been you, Joel would be halfway to Seattle
- before the sun came up. - He'd be halfway to Seattle
他那么做一定是为了救我的命
to save my life.
But when we lost people, no.
可我们现在有伤亡,还不能走
It would just break him like it was his fault.
换他也会崩溃的 他会把一切责任揽到自己身上
I saw that time and time again.
我见过很多次了,别以为我不了解他
And don't talk to me like I didn't know him.
他是我哥哥
He was my brother.
听着,我不是说你不该去
Listen, I'm not sayin' you shouldn't do this.
但是既然要组队 就得组一支像样的队伍
But if we're gonna put a posse together,
we gotta do it right, which means taking it to Maria.
把这件事告诉玛丽亚 没错,必须告诉她
Yes, it's fuckin' necessary.
She's gonna want a council meeting, open it up to the town.
她会召开议会,通知全镇
Everyone who wants to get heard gets heard.
每个想发声的人都能发声
但你会支持我们的,对吧?
But you'll back us, right?
当然
Of course, I will.
过来
Come here.
还有你
And you, you hold out information on me again,
你要是再有事瞒着我 就去最累的岗位上待一个月
you got rendering detail for a month.
好了
Alright.
还有,艾莉...
Ellie.
我们把死者埋在镇南十英里的地方了
We buried our dead ten miles south of town.
你可以去看他
If you want to visit him.
去西雅图的时候再去吧
When we're on our way to Seattle.
(普吉特步道 植物园,西雅图步道)
怎么样?
Well?
没人跟来,很安全,继续前进
"No one following. All clear. Keep moving."
Good.
很好
Once we get resettled, I'll teach you to whistle.
等我们重新安顿好 我们会教你吹口哨的
你为什么不能告诉我目的地是哪里?
Why can't you tell me where we're going?
'Cause we don't know yet.
因为我们还不知道
我已经说了我们要去的原因
I've told you the reason we're going.
我知道,但她为什么不能保护我们?
I know, but why can't she just keep us safe?
The Prophet?
先知?
她十年前就死了,康斯坦丝 我可不会指望她帮我们
She's been dead ten years, Constance. I wouldn't count on her to help.
But Ezra said the Prophet is eternal.
但艾斯拉说先知是永生的
Well, she is, in a way.
从某种角度看没错
但先知不是魔法
A prophet isn't magic.
他们只是...
They're just people that see truths hidden from others
能看到别人看不到的真相
and share that truth, no matter what the cost.
并且不计代价分享真相的人
我们的先知也是如此
So it was with our Prophet.
- 没错 - 没错
So it was.
That's how we keep her spirit alive.
我们就是这样让她的精神永存的
遵循她的话语,服从她的教诲 同时保护自己的安全
Follow her words, we obey her teachings, but we keep ourselves safe.
那能给我一把锤子吗?
Then, can I have a hammer?
好
Alright.
告诉我,你觉得更安全了吗?
Tell me, you feel safer?
Yes.
是的
很好
Good.
要知道,我们现在给你的东西
Understand, what we're giving you now,
will keep you far, far safer than a hammer.
会比锤子给你更多的安全感
那就是出离
Distance.
出离家乡
From home.
From war.
出离战争
找掩护!快!
Take cover! Go!
是恶魔吗?
Demons?
是狼
Wolves.
很好,注意旋转,再来
Alright.
Good, but rotate. More.
现在换右边,只打右边
Now, the right side. Just the right side.
Come on, man, that side hurts more.
- 这边伤害更大 - 我注意到了
I noticed.
- 来吧 - 好
- Come on. - Okay.
用力点!坚持住!最后五拳!
Harder.
Harder! Let's go!
Last five.
- 好了,今天到此为止 - 好
There it is, okay. Done for the day.
Okay.
你觉得怎么样?
So, what'd you think?
Well, for someone who sat on their ass
一个无所事事三个月的人能做成这样
for three months, I'm pleasantly surprised.
- 我觉得很惊喜 - 是吗?
- Yeah? - Push-ups?
平时做俯卧撑了?
Yeah, and crunches when they weren't looking.
对,还在他们不注意时卷腹了
Yeah, that'll do it.
这样就行了 再过几周,你就能恢复原来的状态
A few more weeks, and you'll be right back to where you were before.
Nice.
很好
- 也就是你该有的水平的八成 - 随便了,去你的
Which is 80% of where you should have been.
Whatever. Fuck you.
听说你加入议会了
So, I heard you're on the council now.
Yep.
对
那你肯定知道接下来的会议
So, you know about the meeting coming up?
没错,我知道
I know about the meeting coming up.
我能指望你吗?
Can I count on you?
我不能讨论即将开始的投票
I can't discuss upcoming votes.
Seriously? It's me.
- 搞什么?是我啊 - 我知道
I know.
Dude, you were there.
老兄,当时你也在场
I know that too.
这我也知道
我得走了
Gotta go.
老天
Oh, my God.
艾莉
Ellie.
The council won't make up their mind until we hear people speak.
听完大家的意见,议会才能作决定
So, here's a little advice.
所以我给你一点建议
Organize your thoughts, write them down,
把你的想法整理清楚、写下来 明天念给大家听
and then read 'em out loud tomorrow.
- 知道了,因为我很蠢 - 因为你愤怒,艾莉
Okay, yeah, 'cause I'm stupid.
'Cause you're angry, Ellie.
没人会投票给愤怒的人
And no one's gonna vote for angry.
...所以我一直说我们要多投资火鸡
Which is why I keep saying we need to invest
more in turkeys and less in chickens.
少投资鸡
这就要说回我之前对玉米的看法了
And that brings me back to my earlier point about corn.
Corn, some of you have heard me say,
有些人听我这么说过 玉米不是最容易种植的作物
is not the easiest crop to grow, but it is among the fastest.
但它是生长最快的作物之一
You can plot a graph that shows ease and resources
你们可以绘一张图 把收成时间和所需资源以及难易度...
versus time to harvest and get a li--
斯考特,抱歉打断你,不要偏题
Scott, I'm sorry, but we gotta keep you on target here.
这是公开会议,章程上说...
But it's an open meeting. The bylaws say that--
Maybe we should stick to what everyone else
或许我们应该回到 大家原本要讨论的议程上来
came here to discuss.
I don't really have an opinion on the Seattle thing.
我对西雅图的事没意见
Okay. Thank you.
好,谢谢
斯考特说完了,接下来是瑞秋
So, that was Scott.
Next is Rachel.
Yeah, Joel meant so much to so many of us.
乔尔对我们很多人来说非常重要...
我听不见,大声点
Can't hear you.
Can you take him, please?
- 你能帮我抱着他吗? - 好
Yeah. Okay, here we go.
来吧
我说乔尔对我们很多人来说非常重要
I said that Joel meant so much to so many of us.
But he wasn't the only one.
但他并非唯一一个重要的人
那天我失去了我妹妹
I lost my sister that day.
这里很多人都埋葬了家人
A lot of people in here buried family.
现在你们要派去16个顶尖成员?
And now, you wanna send, what, you're saying 16 of our best?
他们不在的时候,如果掠夺者来了 谁去墙上抵御他们?
Well, while they're gone, who's gonna be on the wall if Raiders come?
A wall that's barely mended.
墙还没修好呢
And none of you up there can promise us that all 16 will come back.
而且谁也不能保证 那16个人都能回来
我同情你们,汤米和艾莉
So, my heart is with you, Tommy and Ellie.
但我们伤亡惨重,现在出击太早了
We are too hurt, and it is too soon.
谢谢你,瑞秋
Thank you, Rachel.
下一位是卡莱尔
Next is Carlisle.
我长话短说,毕竟这是个简单的决定
I'll be quick. 'Cause this one's simple to me.
有人来我们这里
People came and killed Joel.
杀了乔尔
我们为什么不想复仇?
So, why wouldn't we wanna take our vengeance?
因为我们不该那么做
Well, because we're not supposed to.
宽恕他人,方能被人宽恕
Forgive and be forgiven.
放下怨恨和仇恨
No grudges. No revenge.
我都不是基督徒 可我一直觉得这么做很明智
And I'm not even a Christian.
I've always seen the wisdom in that.
That's what separates us from the Raiders and the murderers.
这正是我们与掠夺者和杀人犯 不同的地方
我们懂得仁慈
Our capacity for mercy.
那些混蛋不配得到我们的仁慈
Those sons of bitches don't deserve our mercy.
当然不配,所以才叫仁慈啊
Well, of course they don't deserve it.
- That's what makes it mercy. - Well, to hell with that.
去你的屁话
你能这么说,也不是什么好东西
And to hell with you for saying it, Carlisle.
- Seth, sit down. - No.
- 赛斯,坐下 - 不
- You're not on the list. - No!
- 你不在发言名单上 - 不!
我们到底在说什么?
What the hell are we all talking about here?
哎呦,太不公平了
It's not fair.
我们要原谅每一个 骑在我们头上拉屎的人吗?
What, we gotta forgive everybody when they show up
and piss in our eye?
They came into our house.
他们闯进了我们家
They took one of ours.
抓走了我们的人
天啊
My God, somebody shoots your brother, you wanna take the locks off your doors?
有人射杀了你们的兄弟 你们还想把门锁拆了?
幼稚!
Grow up!
你们这些白痴,他们还会回来的
You idiots, they'll come back.
因为我们没让他们付出代价
They'll come back because we didn't make 'em pay.
等他们回来时,一定带着嘲笑的嘴脸
And when they come back, they'll be laughing.
而你们都活该
And you'll all deserve it.
你们这群...
Bunch of goddamn victims.
该死的受害者
(斯考特、瑞秋、卡莱尔、艾莉)
艾莉?
Ellie?
“我通常不会准备发言稿”
I normally don't write things down
“因为我向来有话直说,不假思索”
because I normally don't think before I talk,
“这让我惹上了不少麻烦”
which has gotten me in trouble before, a lot,
and it's cost me in ways that sometimes couldn't be undone.
“让我付出了无法挽回的代价”
“但我这次输不起 因为我知道我的要求很过分”
But I can't afford that right now, because I know what I'm asking is a lot.
“我要我们在最糟的时机”
I'm asking us to risk more people and resources,
and at the worst possible time.
“拿更多的人力和资源去冒险”
And I want everyone to know, it's not because I want revenge.
“我想告诉大家 我想要的并非复仇”
“真的,这跟复仇无关”
It's not. It's not about revenge.
What I want is what you used to give people.
“我要的是 你们过去给予他人的东西”
“我要正义”
I want justice.
“因为除此之外 就只剩沉默与放弃了”
Because it's either that, or we do nothing.
That's what everyone else out there is going to do for us.
“而外面的人 也只会默默地放弃我们”
Nothing.
“如果我或你们遭遇不幸”
A whole world of people who won't lift a finger
if something bad happens to me or you.
“全世界没有人愿意动一动手指”
“我们有专门的词称呼这种人”
We have a word for these people.
“那就是‘陌生人’”
They're called strangers.
Well, I don't think that we're strangers to each other.
“我觉得我们之间不是陌生人”
And I want to know that I can count on you.
“我得知道我能依靠你们”
And I swear, if someone hurts any of you
“我发誓 如果有人伤害你们或你们爱的人”
or the people you love, you can count on me.
“你们也可以依靠我”
“这才是我们的凝聚力”
That's what holds all this together.
“不是聚餐,也不是跨年舞会”
Not potluck dinners or New Year's Eve dances.
“更不是一堵墙 因为那堵墙已经被撞破了”
Definitely not a wall, because that thing got busted through.
But Jackson is still here.
“而杰克逊依然挺立”
“我会接受议会的一切决议”
I'll accept whatever the council decides.
But I am asking you, please,
“但我拜托你们”
“不惜一切代价伸张正义”
do what it takes to see that justice is done.
“不是为了我”
Not for me. Not even for Joel.
“甚至不是为了乔尔”
“我拜托你们为我们大家这么做”
I am asking you, please, do it for us.
谢谢
Thank you.
议会将就派遣16名成员前往西雅图
The council will now vote on the proposal to send a party of 16 citizens to Seattle
to find the people who killed Joel and execute them.
寻找并处决杀害乔尔之人的提案 进行投票
艾米贝丝?
Amy-Beth?
“赞成”
Yes.
“反对”
No.
“赞成”
Yes.
“反对”
No.
“赞成”
Yes.
No.
“反对”
八票反对,三票赞成,提案被否决了
The vote is 8 to 3. The proposal is rejected.
休庭
Adjourned.
加油,九号球员
Here we go, nine. Here we go.
- 好了,盯紧球! - 快!
Grab the ball!
- 好样的,九号! - 加油,罗德尼,冲啊!
Attaboy, nine!
- 该死 - 他没事
Oh, shit.
I didn't know you were a fan.
我都不知道你是球迷
当然,我当年可买过老虎队的季票呢
Hell, yeah! I had Tigers season tickets.
Get in the game, Charlie.
这其实跟2003年的球队差不多
This actually isn't that far off from the '03 squad.
Louie, stand up! Stand up!
You want a beer? I get them from Marshall.
要喝啤酒吗?我跟马歇尔拿的
今天开会时,我在人群中看到你了
I spotted you in the crowd at the meeting today.
Yeah.
对
我心想
And I thought to myself,
she's probably been extra busy these last few weeks.
“她过去几周可能特别忙”
太残忍了
Brutal.
And I'm supposed to see a shrink myself, you know, to process it all, it's...
我自己都该去看心理医生 消化发生的一切
可这里没有别人了
I'm the only one here.
- 那你怎么办? - 我是个酒鬼
- So, what do you do, then? - Oh, well, I'm an alcoholic.
And I smoke as much weed as I can.
而且我尽可能地多抽大麻
真是一场大灾难
You know, complete fuckin' disaster.
但你来找我不是因为担心我
But you're not here 'cause you're worried about me.
Two outs, guys, two outs. Look alive!
两人出局了,各位,加油!
I don't know.
我不知道
你能看到别人看不到的东西
You see things that others don't.
我担心她会做傻事
I'm nervous she's gonna do somethin' stupid.
- 怎么,你不相信她的发言? - 你相信吗?
What, you didn't believe her speech?
- Did you? - Course not. She's a liar.
当然不信,她是个骗子
撒谎的人不一定是骗子
Well, there's a difference between lyin' and being a liar.
Oh, I know. And that one? Liar.
我知道,她就是骗子
她可能只跟一个人说过实话 而他已经...
There was maybe one person she told the truth to, and he's...
但我们可以在这一点上各持己见
But we can agree to disagree about that.
问题是你很害怕,那我们谈谈吧
What matters is you're afraid. So, let's talk about it.
Okay. Free of charge.
不收钱
我只是不想看她步乔尔的后尘
I just don't want her to go down the same paths that Joel did.
他满口的正当理由
Comin' up with justifications and such.
其实只是在宣泄而已
All he was really doin' was lashin' out.
So, you think she might have learned that behavior from him?
你觉得她的行为可能是跟他学的?
There it is! Keep it up.
其实后天教养的作用微乎其微 其余的都是天性
Turns out nurture can only do this much.
The rest is nature.
If she's on a path, it's not one that Joel put her on.
就算她走上某条路 那也不是乔尔教她的
不是
No. No.
I think they were walking side by side from the very start.
我觉得他们一开始就是并肩而行
汤米,我明白
Tommy, I get it.
现在她归你管了,你想帮她避开麻烦
You inherited her, and you wanna keep her out of trouble.
Take it from a psychotherapist of 40 years.
作为从业40年的心理医生 我劝你一句
有些人...
Some people just...
有些人无法拯救
Some people just can't be saved.
- 是谁? - 迪娜
- Who is it? - Dina.
好吧,你好
Hey.
我要睡了
I'm just going to bed.
No, I don't think that is where you're going.
我不相信
就你一个人吗?
- Are you alone? - I'm alone.
是的
进来
Get in.
Oh, Christ.
天啊
Please don't try and talk me out of this.
- 别劝我放弃 - 你以为我是来劝你的?
You think that's why I'm here?
说说你的计划吧
So, what's your plan?
去西雅图杀死艾比
Go to Seattle and kill Abby.
路线呢?
What route?
西北方
Northwest.
And is that all guns, or do you have medical supplies in there?
这里面都是枪吗?有没有医疗用品?
No?
你最好别在你规划好的西北路线上
Well, better not land weird on an ankle
or get a fever on your well-charted path "northwest."
崴了脚或发高烧
Okay, so what am I supposed to do?
好吧,我该怎么办?
远离高速,避开城市或聚落
Stay off the highways. Steer clear of cities or settlements.
First stage is through the national forest.
第一阶段是穿越国家森林
Once we're out, we follow the Snake River Canyon,
出来后,我们沿蛇河峡谷前进
then break off through the Snoqualmie Pass.
- 然后穿越斯诺夸尔米山口 - 斯诺夸尔米?
Snoqualmie?
Yeah. Snoqualmie.
对,斯诺夸尔米
Approach Seattle from the east, then reassess based on what we find.
从东边接近西雅图 然后根据情况重新做评估
Provisions. Travel light, but smart.
带好粮食,轻装上路,但要聪明
Winter coats for beds, jackets for blankets.
拿厚外套当床垫,拿夹克当被子
First aid kits, batteries, bear spray.
急救箱、电池和防熊喷雾都带上 你要带什么手枪?
Now, handguns. What are you bringing?
这是乔尔的吗?
- Is that Joel's? - Mm-hm.
你打算用这个杀死她
So, that's what you're gonna kill her with?
- Fuckin' right. - Then, save it for that.
- 没错 - 那就留到那时候再用
It's slow and kicks like hell.
它的速度很慢,后坐力特别强
真的吗?你想轰掉你的屁股?
Really? Shoot your damn ass off?
有人这么劝过我
I've heard that before.
我们每人起码得有一百发子弹 加上五十发步枪子弹
We'll want at least 100 shells apiece, plus 50 rifle rounds.
Bring any long gun you want, as long as it's scoped.
你想带什么长枪都可以 只要有瞄准镜就行
Chlorine tablets, a pan, and something to keep Shimmer dry.
氯片、平底锅 还有帮闪闪保持干燥的东西
- Just Shimmer? - Yeah.
- 只带闪闪吗? - 对
We share a horse. Fewer resources.
我们共骑一匹马,减少资源
Everything else is what you'd figure, except this.
其他东西都跟你想的一样,除了这个
靴子
Boots.
我喜欢这双匡威 也尊重你一贯的风格
Love the Converse. Respect your consistency.
But you're not crossing open country in fuckin' Chucks.
但你不能穿帆布鞋横穿荒野
- I've done it before. - No Chucks. Questions?
- 我那么做过 - 不能穿帆布鞋,有问题吗?
Yeah, one. How the fuck are we gonna get all of this?
有一个,我们怎么弄到那么多东西?
I know a guy.
我认识一个人
不是吧,你不会告诉杰西了吧?
Oh, no. No, don't tell me you told Jesse, please.
Captain Wyoming? No.
怀俄明队长?没有
I love the man, but he's a little uptight about rules and shit.
我喜欢他,但他是个死守规矩的人
Wear all the clothes you're gonna bring,
把你要带的衣服都穿上 口袋里装满子弹
fill your pockets with ammo.
其他东西必须装进枪套或背包里
Everything else needs to fit inside a holster or your backpack.
我们凌晨三点在原来的东门见
We'll meet by the old east gate, 3:00 a.m.
凌晨三点
3:00 a.m.
嘿
Hey.
Thank you.
谢谢你
You know, you could have just asked.
其实你可以直接问我的
No, I actually didn't know that.
我不知道你愿意
现在你知道了
Now you do.
跟我换
Trade.
这把枪更好,跟我换
It's better. Trade.
你怎么把它弄出来的?
How'd you get her out?
Jeanine's night watch at the stables.
珍宁在马厩值夜班 她理解我们想做的事
She's sympathetic to our cause.
我们想做的事?
"Our cause"?
You're the one that gave the "us" speech, not me.
是你在议会上说“我们”的 不是我说的
马鞍袋里都是我偷藏的东西
Saddlebags are filled with stuff I had squirreled away.
Two weeks' worth of hardtack, bandages,
能吃两周的硬面包 绷带、酒精、药物和电池
alcohol, meds, batteries.
我想跟你们一起去 但我在跨年夜被友军误伤了
I'd come with you, but I caught some friendly fire on New Year's Day.
- 你确定是友军吗? - 天啊
- You sure it was friendly? - Jesus Christ.
在巡逻队经过之前 你们只有十分钟,快走吧
We got ten minutes before a patrol comes by.
Let's get you going.
(乔尔米勒)
好吧,字母F
Okay, so...
F.
字母F,佛...佛利伍麦克乐团
- Fleetwood Mac. - Nope.
- 不对 - 什么?
What? What do you mean, "no"?
什么叫不对?这是我的看法
- It's my opinion. - Yeah, well,
你的看法是错的 因为弗兰克扎帕真的存在
your opinion is wrong because Frank Zappa exists.
好了,字母G
Okay, so, G.
Green Day.
- 绿日乐队 - 不,你错了
No, you're wrong. It's Guns N' Roses.
Ozzy Osbourne.
奥兹奥斯朋
Nice! Double points.
很好,分数加倍
So, L-M-N-O, P.
L、M、N、O、P
Are you seriously gonna make me do the entire alphabet?
你真要让我猜完所有字母吗?
不用,我很灵活的 让我想想,换个新话题...
We don't have to. I'm incredibly flexible.
Lemme see, new topic.
- 沉默也行 - 有了,你杀的第一个人是谁?
- Or silence. - Got one.
First person you killed.
Jesus, really?
天啊,真的吗?
Yeah, fun stories of childhood.
对,有趣的童年故事
第一个人死得太离谱 但我可以跟你说说第二个
Okay, well, the first one's too fucked up, but I can tell you the second one.
没问题
I accept.
It was a little before Joel and I got to Jackson.
那是我和乔尔来杰克逊之前的事
In Kansas City, he got jumped by this kid, maybe just a couple years older than me.
在堪萨斯城 他被一个没比我大几岁的孩子突袭
我从后面接近他 举起枪,然后...就这样
And I came up behind him, raised my gun and, yeah.
抱歉,艾莉
Sorry, Ellie.
Interesting. I shoot a guy, and you feel sorry for me?
有意思,杀人的是我 你却替我难过?
我就是这么忠诚
I'm just loyal like that.
如果你看到露岩或有遮蔽的地方 记得告诉我
Let me know if you see any outcroppings
- or spots with cover. - Why?
为什么?天气挺好的
It looks okay.
我的天,雨来得真快 你怎么知道会这样的?
Holy shit, that came on fast.
How the fuck did you know that was gonna happen?
- 我是女巫 - 显然是这样
- I'm a witch. - Clearly.
晚安
Well, good night.
Night.
不过,我还有个蠢问题
Okay, but I have a stupid question.
和跨年夜有关
It's about New Year's Eve, and, you know,
那个吻
the kiss.
好,也没什么,你当时嗑嗨了
Okay.
I mean, whatever, you were super high.
And you were drunk.
而你醉了
对,所以那不能代表什么 你是想问这个吧
Right, so it doesn't mean anything,
- if that's what you're asking. - No, I know that.
不,这个我知道,我想问的是
My question is,
how would you rate it?
你会给那个吻打几分?
- 一到十分? - 不
- Scale of one to ten. - No.
Come on.
拜托,你以前吻过女孩
You've kissed girls before. You're gay, I'm not.
你是同性恋,而我不是
我只是好奇,我想知道我厉不厉害
I'm just curious. I wanna know if I'm any good at it.
一到十分
One to ten.
好吧,六分
Okay, fine. Six.
Fuck you, "six."
- 去你的,六分! - 这算不错了
- That's not bad. - That sucks!
真是烂透了!
What?
什么?
For the record, I don't believe you.
郑重声明一下,我不相信你
你非要问,我就答了,对不起
Well, you asked, and I told you. I'm sorry.
你可以回去找杰西
You can go back to Jesse.
I already did.
我已经找了
那就行了
Well, there you have it.
他有没有给你一种悲伤的感觉?
Does he ever strike you as sad?
杰西吗?有
Jesse? Yeah.
他跟你说过原因吗?
Has he ever told you why?
没有
No.
但我觉得他内心深处就是悲伤的人
But I think deep inside, that's just how he is.
- 至少我希望是这样 - 为什么?
- At least, I hope that's why. - Why would you hope that?
因为如果不是的话...
Well, because if it's not that,
那就是我的问题了
then it's me.
晚安
Well, good night.
Night.
艾莉?
Ellie?
当时我没那么嗨
I wasn't that high.
(植物园,西雅图步道)
还有多远?
- How much further? - Close.
很近了
大约十英里
Maybe ten miles?
In theory, we'll come out near Highway Five, just north of the city.
理论上 我们会从城北五号公路附近穿出去
他死前正在逃跑
He was running away.
What's that symbol?
这是什么符号?
不知道,我也是第一次见
I don't know, I've never seen it before.
子弹的口径各不相同 应该不是联邦救灾局干的
A lot of different calibers. I don't think this was FEDRA.
迪娜
Dina.
Dina?
迪娜?
Move.
You okay?
- 你没事吧? - 那边...
It's just...
你没事吧?
Doing okay?
对不起,我从没有过这种反应
Yeah, I'm sorry, it's just that's never happened before.
- 可能是气味太重 - 而且惨不忍睹
I think it was the smell.
It wasn't easy to look at either.
If this was fucking them,
如果这是他们干的...
如果艾比和她的人能对人干出这种事
if Abby and her crew did this to people,
to kids?
能杀害孩子...
对
Yeah.
走吧
Let's go.
已经很接近了
We're close now.
(警告,接近监控区,联邦救灾局)
好安静
It's quiet.
Yeah. Too quiet.
对,过于安静了
柯蒂斯还是毒蛇的台词?
- Curtis or Viper? - Both, in all four movies.
都有,他们在四部电影里都说过
(西雅图,九英里)
Nine more miles.
还有九英里
九英里
Nine more.
该死的西雅图,真漂亮
Fucking Seattle. Pretty.
而且也没人对我们开枪
Plus, no one's shooting at us.
看来狼也没那么多嘛
I guess there aren't that many Wolves.
马上就要少很多了
There's about to be a whole lot less.
- 柯蒂斯还是毒蛇的台词? - 什么?
Curtis or Viper?
What?
不,是我自创的 我只是想显得我厉害一点
No, that was just me. I was trying to sound like a badass.
你本来就很厉害
You don't need to try.
“曼尼”
Manny.
是我,说吧
Yeah, go ahead.
We're moving up to the FOB.
“我们要前往前进作战基地 三号和五号检查站之间安全吗?”
All clear between checkpoint three and five?
Told me to watch six and eight.
明明叫我盯着六号和八号 现在又问三号和五号
Now, they want fuckin' three and five.
“曼尼,听到了吗?”
Manny, you copy?
Just give me a fuckin' second. Jesus.
等我一分钟,真是的
没问题,可以往前走了
You're all good. You can move up.
(华盛顿解放阵线)
待续
谢谢观赏